# **Utomudo Theodora**

# Front End Developer

Front end developer with two years of experience delivering excellent user experiences with JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, React Js, and Angular. Adept at contributing to a highly-collaborative work atmosphere, solving problems, and meeting client satisfaction.

Lagos, Nigeria +234 7057552262 utomudotheodora@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/theodora-utom udo-171a3a1a0

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# LifeBank, Lagos, Nigeria

## **Front End Engineer**

#### January 2021 - Present

- Overhauled the UI and developed user dashboard for an internal tool to create visibility for product growth, which helped the user increase productivity, and reduce data load time by 80%.
- Partnered with data science to develop the front end for a product that creates data visibility for various products by 70%.
- Developed and designed an internal tool to track product stock level and value which helped improve inventory management by 70%.

# LifeBank, Lagos, Nigeria

# Product Manager

#### October 2020 - Present

- Designed user flow using flow chart for product features which created clarity on product design by 90%.
- Created user stories for product features which provided a better understanding of product requirements by 90%.
- Created boards with Jira for tracking product backlog, which increased productivity and time management by 80%.

# LifeBank, Lagos Nigeria

# Front End Engineer Intern

### March 2020 - January 2021

- Developed and Maintained a public landing page for product campaign for 5 cities which increased product growth by 50%.
- Developed and designed admin dashboard with another developer for growth visibility with 3 secure user logins.
- Developed and designed a Hand wash App for user hygiene awareness about the covid-19 virus.

#### **SKILLS**

**CSS** 

Boostrap

HTML

Scrum

React Is

Angular

JavaScript

**Typescript** 

#### **EDUCATION**

# Delta State University of Science and Technology

HND in Computer Science September 2018

Delta State, Nigeria

- Completed six months
   Front End Development
   course with Findworka
   Academy
- Completed one-day soft skill training with Jobberman.
- Completed three weeks Bootcamp Web/ Agile Lean development with Africa Agility

#### **OTHER**

- FRONT END DEVELOPERcertified (2020)
- WEB /AGILE LEAN DEVELOPMENTcertified (2021)
- SCRUM MASTER-certified (2021)